Now that Sintel's full shapes are completed
现在SINTEL的所有表情就完整了
the next step is to create a symmetrical one using "Vertex Groups Weight Painting"
下一步将要使用“顶点组权重绘制”来创建它对称的部分
in the "Property" panel under "Vertex Group"
在“Vertex Group"的"Property"面板中
I created a new group
我创建了一个新的组
and named it "Face_L"
把它命名为“face_l"
in Edit mode I select the central edge loop using Shift Alt Right Mouse Button
在编辑模式下，我按着shift及alt和鼠标右键选择了中间的这个环边
I then hide the selection with the H key
然后我按H把选的这条边隐藏掉
Moving the mouth into Sintel's right side
现在把鼠标移到右边
I press L to select the linked
我按L去选择所有LINKED边
back to the "Vertex Group" panel
回到"Vertex Group"面板
I assign those vertex a weight of 0
我指定这些顶点的权重为0
then deselect all using A
然后按A取消选择
the same is done to Sintel's left side
然后再左边做相同的操作
but this time the weight value is changed to 1
但是切记左边的权重要设为1而不是0
with the left and right side now done
现在左右边都好了
I un-hide the central edge loop using Alt H
我按ALT+H取消隐藏中间的环边
and assign the center a weight of 0.5
然后把它的权重设为0.5
weight value of selected vertex can be seen in the Property shelf under Vertex Groups
顶点的权重值可以在属性栏的顶点组部分看到
next step is to create a smoother transition
下一步是创建一个平稳的过渡
to do this
要做到这个
I edge-loop select the next span over in the left side
我要选择中间往左的一排边
and assign it a weight of 0.8
把它的权重设为0.8
the same is done to the right side
在右边脸也要这样做
but this time I assign it 0.2
但右边权重设置为0.2
whatever the value on one side
无论哪一边的权重值是多少
the mirrored side must equal a total of 100%
镜像的两边加起来权重必须等于1
this way
这样
when combined together
当他们合在一起时
it fix back exactly to the full shape
才会准确的定位在所有的表情上
you can also use Ctrl V key to blend vertex groups
以上这些操作你也可以使用CTRL+V菜单里的“blend vertex groups"实现
but for this purpose
但是在这里
I prefer the position I can get by assigning directly selected vertex
我比较喜欢自己亲自操作边和顶点的权重
let's switch the mode to Weight Paint
现在让我们切换成权重喷涂模式
and select the face's left vertex group to display the assignment
选择左边脸的顶点组去显示他们的设定值
from here I usually go back and tweak the weights a little bit more
这里我经常看情况稍微修改一下权重
back to Edit mode
返回编辑模式
I copy and paste the face's left vertex group name into the Shapes Key panel under each shape
我将这个左边脸的顶点组名字拷贝进所有表情的"shapes key panel"中
example for "MOUTH-up", "MOUTH-dn", "MOUTH-L" and "MOUTH-twist"
除了"mouth-up","mouth-dn","mouth-l"和"mouth-twist"
here I'm using the Up Arrow to scroll through the list
这里我用上箭头在列表里切换
let's activate the Paint button here
然后我们激活paint按钮，在这里
to quickly go over the shapes
然后浏览下所有的表情
having Paint button activated will always show that current shape at the full one value
把PAINT按钮打开后，就会看到当前表情动作幅度最大时候的状态。
overwriting any other shape with values
切换时会覆盖上个表情
in Object mode I select the "smile.L" to add its full value of 1
在物体模式下，我选择"smile.L"，设置表情值为1
select the + button to add new shape
点"+"按钮，增加一个新表情
the X button clears all shapes to 0
X按钮会清除所有表情幅度值为0
I rename this new shape "MOUTH-Smile.L"
然后把这个新建的表情重命名为"Mouth-smaile.l"
next I create a duplicate of that shape
下一步我又复制了这个表情
clear all shape and by copying and pasting the "MOUTH-Smile.L"
清除所有的表情幅度值，把复制来的表情改名为
I replace the "L" with "R" for right
"Mouth-smile.R"，这就是右脸微笑表情
having this right shape selected
选择这个右脸的表情
I then click on Mirror Shape Key which flips the shape to the right
点"mirror shape"键将表情镜像到右边去 （本来是左脸表情复制来的，必须镜像到右脸的）
dialing both values of left and right to 1 recreates the full smile shape
把左右脸微笑动作幅值都打到1，然后按+键创建个完整微笑表情
for the "MOUTH-L" shape and the "MOUTH-twist.L" shape
至于"mouth-l"和"mouth-twist.L"表情（都是左脸的）
the right side is created by simply using Mirror Shape Key
就和上面微笑的创建方法一样用镜像功能去创建相应的右脸表情
"MOUTH-up" shape and "MOUTH-down" shape are left as is
"mouth-up" 表情 和"mouth-down"表情就别管了，扔那 （因为上下动作本来就是左右对称的）
you can always create a new shape key by blending existing ones
有个好处就是你可以从现有的表情混合而得来新表情
here I'm combining the "MOUTH-L" with the "MOUTH-twist.L"
现在我要混合"mouth-l"和"mouth-twist.l"
Here I'm expanding the window using Shift and Middle Mouse Scroll
我按shift+鼠标滚轮去扩展这个窗口
all 28 symmetrical shapes have been divided up to create a total of 55 split shapes
所有28个对称的表情被分成55个独立的表情
including the pupil dilation
包括瞳孔缩放
at this stage I create the coinsiding shapes for the inner mouth geometry
在这个场景里我创建了嘴内部同时运动部分的几何体的表情
as well as the eyebrow emitter and lashes
而且也作了眉毛和睫毛的表情
once all shapes are completed and named properly
一旦所有的表情都完成了而且赋予了正确名字
the next step is to hook these shapes up to the facial rig
下一步就是将其挂到表情链接骨骼上
using the same vertex weighting method
方法是一样的顶点权重法
brows up and down get split in four shapes
眉毛上下运动被分成了四个表情
left inner and outer
左边内部和外部
and right inner and outer
以及右边内部和外部
here is a Wire view of the mouth shapes working with the facial shapes
这里是嘴内部表情共同运动时的框线动画